LinkedIn in



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Certified UX | UI designer with a diploma in industrial design and a specialisation in online marketing. Experience in medical technology and textile printing. Special knowledge in print data creation, content management, online marketing and graphic design. Development of graphic design projects (logos, flyers, advertisements, infographics)

and the company's own online shop (entire design, text). Skilled in the implementation of the entire UX design thinking process for responsive digital applications. Expert in user research, user personas, wireframing, prototyping and the entire visual design process with Adobe Creative Cloud, Adobe XD and Figma.

UI UX DESIGN SKILLS

Methodology

Design Thinking Process · User-Centered Design · Service Design · Lean UX

Research

Competitive & SWOT Analysis · User Interviews · User Surveys · User Personas · User Stories · User Flows

Design

UI Design · Style Guide · Brand Design Typography · Iconography · Grid System Visual Hierarchy · Responsive Design · Mobile-First-Design · Wireframing (low, mid, high fidelity) · Crazy 8 · Prototyping & Animation · Mockups · HTML & CSS Basics

Testing

Usability Tests · A | B Testing · Preference Tests

UI UX DESIGN TOOLS

Adobe Creative Suite · Figma & FigJam · Adobe XD · InVision · Usability Hub · Slack · MS Office · SEO & SEA · Wordpress · Elementor · Joomla · Clever Reach · Photography

EDUCATION

UI Design Certificate

CareerFoundry | 07/2022-05/2023 https://careerfoundry.com

Online Marketing Manager

HK Hamburg | 04/2019

Diploma Industrial Design

FH Darmstadt | 10/2010 - 02/2016

LANGUAGE

German mother tongue English fluent Spanish advanced

UI|UX DESIGN PROJECTS

grow | Responsive Finance App (all devices)

CareerFoundry | 01/2023 - 02/2023

Created an accessible finance app to optimise navigation and use and to increase trust. Developed brand guidelines, user flows, wireframes (low, mid, high fidelity) and prototypes with animation, designed final UI and mockups used Figma, Illustrator and Slack. Case Study

LightDays | Native Menstrual Cycle App

CareerFoundry | 11/2022 - 12/2022

Developed the iOS and Android version of a native app to identify symptoms that occur during the menstrual cycle. Conducted user surveys and interviews, analysed and implemented user feedback, developed user flows, created wireframes with Crazy 8 method, prototypes with animations and designed the final UI with Figma to optimise the navigation and the visual design. Case Study

TooGood | Respnsive Recipe Web App (all devices)

CareerFoundry | 10/2022 - 11/2022

Designed a responsive web app for recipes to optimise navigation and use. Focused on filters for the most popular diets to increase the number of returning users. Conducted competitive and SWOT analysis, preference tests, user surveys and interviews with Slack and UsabilityHub. Developed user flows, wireframes and prototyping. Applied layout grids and defined responsive grid breakpoints. Designed patterns, mood boards, brand guidelines, layout systems, mockups and the final UI with Adobe Creative Suite, Figma and FigJam. Case Study

WORK HISTORY

Marketing & Design | FahnenFleck GmbH & Co. KG

Hamburg, Germany | 01/2017 - Present

- Designed the companies online shop and successfully increased sales after launch by 50% within a one-year period through visual hierarchy, professional product photography, conception and design of marketing campaigns such as for social media and improved SEO text used Adobe Creative Suite, MS Office, Joomla, Clever Reach.
- Improved the user interface of the new online shop to implement new software used Adobe XD, which was a great opportunity to gain experience in UX | UI over a period of 6 years.

Graphic Design | Leben im Abseits e.V (Volunteer Work)

Hamburg, Germany | Remote | 08/2020 - Present

- Supported an organisation to raise awareness for homeless people. Exchanged with stakeholders to optimise short decision processes.
- Designed flyers, business cards, information brochures and exhibition materials to increase the number of visitors at events such as readings used Adobe Creative Suite and MS Office.

Freelancer in industrial design | Puls

Darmstadt, Germany | 08/2015 - 10/2015

Redesign of a user interface for Medozon Compact. Minimised user errors through successful developed of user guidance and visual hierarchy within 5 months period used Adobe Creative Suite and MS Office.

Internship Industrial Design | Tchibo

Hamburg, Germany | 04/2014 - 09/2014

Successfully developed and designed products for serial production to meet deadlines within 3-6 month period. Researched phase themes, created mood boards and graphic designs as well as 3D models used Adobe Creative Suite, MS Office and Rhino.